https://www.johnnyseeds.com/customer-support/privacy-policy.html?source=cookieinfo

Last updated 12.09.2020
At Johnny's Selected Seeds, we respect the privacy of our customers and the importance of the information they entrust to us. We have summarized below our basic information policies and practices for this Web site, www.johnnyseeds.com, which is owned and operated by Johnny's Selected Seeds. It is our intent to ensure this Privacy Policy is complete and current with best privacy practices. If at any time you have questions or concerns about your privacy or security with our company, please call us at 877-564-6697 or email us at privacy@johnnyseeds.com.
Top ˆ
Information Usage
Uses of Personal Information.
We collect identifiers and personal information on our Web site when you make a purchase, create an online account, request a catalog, or subscribe to email. Identifiers and personal information may include your name, address, email address, and credit card number. We collect and use such information to enhance your customer experience with us and for marketing purposes such as to:
Process, track, and fill your orders
Help make the site easier for you to use
Provide you with relevant information and content
Market our products and seeds
Inform you of special offers and promotions
Include you in customer surveys
Some special notes about e-mail:
If you complete a Johnny's Selected Seeds survey, we may record your email address along with the information you provide us on the questionnaire. We use summaries of the data collected from our surveys to help us improve the service and products we offer you.
Your email address also allows us to send you an order confirmation and customer service messages as necessary. If you have subscribed to our marketing and newsletter emails, we will also send you useful growing tips, special offers, customer surveys, and new product updates. We provide instructions on how to unsubscribe in each email.
Uses of Log Files.
In addition, certain anonymous Information is collected automatically by our Web site. This information may include visitor domain name, IP address, and referring domain. The information is tracked in server logs, and may be used to troubleshoot problems, keep content relevant, examine traffic trends, and improve the Web site experience for visitors. This anonymous information is used only in aggregate form.
Uses of Cookies and Other Technology. We may assign your computer one or more Cookies, which are a standard Internet tool. A Cookie is a small data file stored as text files by your Web browser on your computer's hard drive. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept Cookies. You can set your browser to refuse Cookies from Web sites or remove them from your device, but this will cause certain functions of our site to not work properly. We use Cookies, "web beacons," and other similar technologies to collect information in connection with our Web site and advertising efforts.  For example, we use Cookies to enable you to save products in your shopping cart while you browse our Web site, and our Web site may use your browsing activity on our Web site to recommend other products you may be interested in.  We also use Cookies and other technology to analyze the effectiveness of our Web site and our advertising efforts, and we may use these technologies to display personalized advertising tailored to your interests as you browse the web.  To learn more about interest-based advertising, and your choices about it, please see "Your Choices About Interest-Based Advertising," below.
Top ˆ
Your Choices About Interest-Based Advertising
We work with third-party advertising companies to more effectively target our advertising messages.  These third-party advertising platforms collect information about your browsing activity on our Web site and across the Internet, and analyze that information in order to display more relevant ads to you.  For example, if you search for a particular product on our Web site, you may be shown an advertisement for that product or a similar product when you are browsing a different Web site.
Our Web site is not configured to recognize a "do not track" signal from a web browser.  If you would like to opt-out of interest-based advertising, you may visit the Network Advertising Initiative's Consumer Opt-Out Link and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance's Consumer Opt-Out Link and on those sites, you may opt-out of receiving tailored advertising from companies that help serve those ads.
Top ˆ
Privacy of Minors
Our Web site is not intended for children under 16 years of age. No one under age 16 may provide any personal information on the Web site. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If you are under 16, do not use or provide any information on this Web site. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.
Top ˆ
Data Security and Safety
We are committed to maintaining appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative measures to safeguard the security of your personal information.
However, if you have any concerns about ordering electronically, feel free to call
1-877-564-6697
to place your order over the phone.
You can also print your online shopping cart page and fax your order:
Attention: Customer Service
1-800-738-6314 (US Only)
1-207-238-5375 (Non-US)
Or, you can mail your order to us at the following address:
Johnny's Selected Seeds
ATTN: Catalog Order
PO Box 299
Waterville, ME 04903
Top ˆ
YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
If you are a California resident, the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) provides you with certain rights regarding your personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and how to exercise them.
Information We Collect and How It Is Used
We collect information from you in several different ways on this site, with the goal of improving your customer experience with Johnny's Selected Seeds. During the past 12 months, we have collected the following types of information:
Identifiers, such as a real names, aliases, postal addresses, unique personal identifiers, online identifiers, Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, email addresses, or other similar identifiers;
Collected from: Information you provide to us, or we collect when you use our services or Web site.
Business use: To enable the use of our Web site, fulfill your orders, market our products and seeds, inform you of special offers and promotions, communicate directly with you, and understand how customers interact with our Web site and offerings.
For our commercial customers applying for credit, we also collect identifiers such as social security numbers for the purpose of processing that application.
Categories of personal information (Section 1798.80(e) of the Cal. Civil Code), such as telephone numbers, credit card numbers, debit card numbers, and other financial information;
Collected from: Information you provide to us, or we collect when you use our services or Web site.
Business use: To fulfill your orders, communicate directly with you, and prevent fraud.
Internet or other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to, browsing history, search history, and information regarding a consumer's interaction with an Internet Web site, application, or advertisement;
Collected from: Information we collect when you use our services or Web site.
Business use: To enable the use of our Web site, monitor and troubleshoot Web site performance, provide you with relevant information and content, market our products and seeds, inform you of special offers and promotions, improve our offerings, detect fraud, and assist with your requests.
Commercial information, including records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies;
Collected from: Information you provide to us, or we collect when you use our services or Web site.
Business use: To enable the use of our Web site, fulfill your orders, market our products and seeds, inform you of special offers and promotions, communicate directly with you, and understand how customers interact with our Web site and offerings.
For our commercial customers applying for credit, we also collect additional commercial information for the purposes of processing that application.
Geolocation data; and
Collected from: Information we collect when you use our services or Web site; information provided by third parties.
Business use: To enable the use of our Web site and to personalize your experience; and for fraud detection.
Inferences, system-generated predictions about your interests and preferences
Collected from: Created internally and with the help of our business partners.
Business use: To personalize your experience and improve our offerings.
Top ˆ
How Information May Be Shared
During the past 12 months, we have shared the following information for business purposes. Please note that for purposes of this notice, personal information does not include deidentified, aggregated, or anonymized information that is maintained in a form that is not capable of being associated with or linked to you.
Sale for a Business Purpose:
We do not sell your personal information for any monetary consideration. However, under some circumstances a transfer of personal information to a third party without monetary consideration may still be considered a "sale" under California law. If you purchase from us, Johnny's Selected Seeds may opt your name, address, email address, and order information into a cooperative marketing database used by other companies that may want to market goods or services to you.
If you wish to opt out of the sale of personal information, please use the following link: DO NOT SELL MY PERSONAL INFORMATION. You may authorize another to submit a request to opt out on your behalf, but only if you provide the authorized agent with signed, written permission to do so. So as to ensure your privacy, we reserve the right to deny a request from an authorized agent who does not submit proof that they have been authorized to act on your behalf. If exercised, the decision to opt out will be valid for 12 months, at which time we may request that you authorize the sale of personal information again.
Disclosure for a Business Purpose:
THIRD PARTY
PURPOSE
CATEGORY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Operating system and platform
Calculation of sales tax
Identifiers: Name and customer address
Commercial information: Order information
Operating system and platform
Operating system and platform
Transactional emails (order confirmations, password resets, etc.) and order management and fulfillment
Identifiers: Name; bill-to and ship-to addresses; email address; and telephone number.
Commercial information: Order information
Operating system and platform
Drop-ship vendors
Shipping
Identifiers: Name and customer address
Commercial information: Order information
Operating system and platform
Customer support
Identifiers: Customer email address; name; telephone number; and zip code
Data analytics providers
Web site analytics/improving our products and services
Internet information: Browsing history and browser information
Commercial information: Order information
Geolocation data
Identifiers: IP address
Inferences: System-generated predictions about your interests and preferences
Social networks
Advertising networks
Data analytics providers
Operating system and platform
Online advertising and product recommendations
Internet information: Browsing history and browser information
Identifiers: IP address; email address; unique personal identifiers
Geolocation data
Commercial information: Order information
Top ˆ
Exercise of Your Data Rights
You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and verify your request, we will disclose to you:
The categories of personal information we collected about you.
The categories of sources from which the personal information has been collected.
The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you.
Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling any personal information.
The categories of personal information about you that was sold or disclosed for a business purpose.
The categories of third parties to whom the personal information was sold or disclosed for a business purpose, by category or categories of personal information for each category of third parties to whom the personal information was sold.
You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and verify your request, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies.
We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service providers to:
Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our agreement with you.
Detect security incidents; protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity; or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act.
Enable internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
Comply with a legal obligation.
Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.
To exercise the rights described above, please submit a verifiable request to us through our CCPA INFORMATION REQUEST FORM, calling us at 877-564-6697, or emailing us at privacy@johnnyseeds.com.
Only you or a person whom you authorize to act on your behalf may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. If you wish to authorize another to act on your behalf, please be advised that we may require that you provide the authorized agent with signed written permission to submit a request and verify your own identity and confirm your permission directly with us, unless the authorized agent has a power of attorney. However, you may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child.
Our verification process works as follows. Before we may process a request, in order to protect your privacy, we will ask for you to confirm a few pieces of information that we have on our records about you, for example:
Your address
Your zip code
Your most recent purchase
Your email address
If you make a request online to delete your personal information, we may need to confirm your request before we delete your information.
You may make a verifiable consumer request up to two times within a 12-month period, without charge. Unfortunately, we cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm that the personal information relates to you. Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor's identity or authority to make the request.
We try to respond to a verifiable consumer request within 45 days of its receipt. If we require more time, we will inform you of the reason and extension time period (up to 90 days). If you have an account with us, we will deliver our response to that account. If you do not have an account with us, we will deliver our response by mail or electronically, at your option. Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding receipt. The response we provide will also explain any reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable.
If you wish to opt out of the sale of personal information, please use the following link: DO NOT SELL MY PERSONAL INFORMATION. You may authorize another to submit a request to opt out on your behalf, but only if you provide the authorized agent with signed, written permission to do so. So as to ensure your privacy, we reserve the right to deny a request from an authorized agent who does not submit proof that they have been authorized to act on your behalf. If exercised, the decision to opt out will be valid for 12 months, at which time we may request that you authorize the sale of personal information again.
We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights.
Top ˆ
PRIVACY POLICY
Click for downloadable, printable, PDF version of our Privacy Policy.
PRINTABLE PDF
ON THIS PAGE
Information Usage
Your Choices About Interest-Based Advertising
Privacy of Minors
Data Security and Safety
Your California Rights
• Information We Collect and How It Is Used
• How Information May Be Shared
• Exercise of Your Data Rights
This site uses cookies to personalize your experience, measure site performance, and show you relevant offers and advertisements. To learn more about our use of cookies, as well as the categories of personal information we collect and your choices, please read our Privacy Policy. By clicking ALLOW or clicking on any other content, you agree that cookies can be placed.
allow
